上季回顾《犯罪心理：演变》...
Last season on Criminal Minds: Evolution...
我们正在追捕连环杀手网络的首脑
We are pursuing the leader of a network of serial killers.
凶手埃利亚斯·沃伊特集结追随者
The unsub, Elias Voit, gathered followers
现已全面启动计划
that he's now activating.
这是张庞大的网
This is a network.
听说有人
What is this I'm hearing about
把简历
a certain résumé being submitted
投给了匡提科？
by a certain someone to Quantico?
我是给人事部递了简历
I've given HR my résumé.
但他们还没点头
They haven't said yes yet,
- 不过... - 他们肯定会同意
- but... - They're gonna say yes.
这事瞒多久了？
How long has this been going on?
几周而已
A couple weeks.
我们觉得分开比在一起
We, you know, we decided that
更痛苦
we're more miserable apart than together.
司法部已批准
The DOJ is prepared
他有权这么做？
He can do that?
和杀人魔合作？
Just agree to work with a prolific killer?
行为分析组必须与沃伊特合作
The BAU will work with Elias Voit.
- 绝不 - 你们别无选择
- We will not. - Oh, you most certainly will.
我们绝不会
We will not
接受连环杀手的"帮助"
rely on help from a serial killer.
我们会配合
We'll cooperate.
麦迪逊局长认可沃伊特的认罪协议
Director Madison is honoring Voit's plea agreement.
他将被转移至
Which means he is going to be transferred
科利摩尔联邦监狱
to FCI Collymore,
低安全级别监狱
a minimum-security federal prison.
没人觉得奇怪吗？
Isn't it weird to anyone else that Voit wants
沃伊特坚持要进普通监区
to be in general population?
你就是沃伊特对吧？
You're Elias Voit, aren't you?
我叫李·杜瓦尔 你们抓错人了
Nah, uh, Lee Duval. You got the wrong guy.
不 你就是沃伊特
No, you're Voit.
别闹了 认真的吗？
Come on, seriously?
老兄 我这次真没开玩笑
Dude, I'm being completely serious.
怎么办？截止日期铁定赶不上
Well, what are we gonna do? We can't make that deadline.
明早必须给出解决方案
We need to have an answer by tomorrow.
行吧 明早再想辙
Fine, we'll figure it out tomorrow.
- 晚安 - 晚安
- Good night. - Good night.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我完全迷路了
I'm, like, totally lost.
想去贝瑟尼海滩该怎么走？
and I'm trying to find Bethany Beach.
我离得近吗？
Am I-am I close?
问错人了 我也是刚搬来的
You're asking the wrong guy. I'm new here.
我也是 刚才谷歌地图还好好的
Yeah, me, too. Google Maps was working great
突然就没信号了
and then I just, like, lost all my bars.
你懂的 信号说没就没
You know what I mean? When you have service and then, uhp,
- 彻底断联 - 对对 深有体会
- no, you don't. - Yeah, I-I know what you mean.
我这还有两格信号
I've got two bars.
告诉我地址 我帮你查
If you give me the address, I can look it up for you.
地址是 11...
Yeah, it's, uh, one, one,
40...
four, zero.
什么...
Wha...
调度中心 发现疑似10-14事件
Dispatch, we got a possible 10-14.
停车检查 完毕
Stopping to investigate. Over.
嘿 伙计
Hey. Buddy.
你还好吗？
You okay?
不好
No.
今晚磕了多少啊？
How much you take tonight, huh?
要叫救护车吗？
You need an ambulance?
警官 我能...
Officer, can I...
- 借一步说话吗？- 救我
- can I talk to you for a second? - Help me.
救命
Help.
其实是...
It's, uh,
我哥他...
it's my big brother. He's-he's, uh,
他是个瘾君子 具体剂量不清楚
he's a junkie. I-I don't really know how much he took,
爸妈为这事操碎了心
but it's pretty tough on my mom and dad.
他们还不知道
They don't know.
看起来像是脸着地摔的
It looks like he just fell on his face.
他应该常来这买货
You know? This is where he comes to get his shit, I think,
但我不太确定
but I-I don't really know.
我只想带他回家
I-I just kind of want to get him home.
不 不
No. No.
看谁回来了
Hey, look who's back.
你今晚差点没命 伙计
You almost died tonight, pal.
回家路上小心
Get home safe.
救命 救命
Help. Help.
喜欢玩水吗？
Do you like the water?
♪ 活出我的精彩 ♪
♪ Living the life I know ♪
♪ 看夕阳西下... ♪
♪ Watching the sun set... ♪
天 她这也太饥渴了
Oh, man. She is so thirsty. -
这种视频发上网绝对爆火
I bet if we posted something like that, it would go viral.
咱们必须拍一个
We should totally do that.
公牛鲨能适应咸淡水环境
Bull sharks can live in both salt and fresh water.
快看这条 兄弟
Hey, check it, bruv. Look at this one.
甲壳类 海洋哺乳动物 鸟类
Crustaceans, marine mammals, birds, -
海龟 什么都吃...
turtles, anything that...
烦死了 真受不了
I hate this so much. This is so annoying.
我得再来一杯
I need another drink.
♪ 天旋地转让我... ♪
♪ Spinning around got me... ♪
我们去哪？
Where are we going?
去游泳啊 傻冒
I'm going swimming. Dumbass.
等等 我也去
Hold up. I'll come, too.
又没邀请你
I didn't invite you.
想一个人去？
What, you gonna go swimming all by yourself?
得有个救生员看着吧
Seems to me you need a lifeguard,
我自愿当护花使者
and I volunteer as tribute.
今晚喝了多少啤酒？
How many beers have you had tonight?
- 什么？- 喝了多少？
- What? - How many beers?
- 没数 - 我数了
- I don't know. - I do.
- 六瓶 - 你还数了？
- Six. - You counted?
- 对 - 为什么？
- Yeah. - Why?
我一个女生在派对上得保持清醒
Because I'm a woman at a party by herself.
- 就这原因 - 我没醉
- That's why. - I'm not drunk.
这可不好说
That's debatable.
但你的电子烟整晚没停过
What isn't is that you've been hitting your vape pen all night.
一 你闻起来像泡在凯蒂猫香水里
Which means, A, you smell like a concentrated Hello Kitty,
二 你肺活量根本不行
and, B, you do not have the lung capacity
跟不上我的节奏
to keep up with me.
知道我怎么想吗？
Well, you know what I think?
你就是个自命清高的贱人
I think you're a stuck-up bitch who thinks she's better
- 觉得谁都配不上你 - 只有你配不上
- than everyone else. - Not everyone. Just you.
帮个忙 滚远点
So do me a favor. Fuck off.
- 等等... - 贱人 我练过综合格斗
- Wait. W-W... - Bitch, I know MMA.
看那边
No, look.
天啊
Oh, my God.
你下来前都没发现异常？
You didn't notice anything wrong until you got down here?
没有 我得盯着
No. I had to keep my eye
那边的白马王子啊
on Prince Charming over there. -
还有别的事吗？
Look, do you need me for anything else?
- 我能走了吗？- 可以 但别离开本地
- Can I go? - You can, but don't leave town.
这地界十年没出过这种案子了
We haven't had a case like this round these parts in ten years.
事实上 警长 这案子可能
Actually, Sheriff, this might not be
不归你管了
your case at all.
- 你们是谁？- 高级探员普伦蒂斯
- Who are you? - SSAs Prentiss,
罗西和贾饶
Rossi and Jareau,
隶属FBI行为分析部
Behavioral Analysis Unit of the FBI.
FBI？你们来干嘛？
FBI? What's the FBI doing here?
确认这具尸体的特征是否与其他四具
Seeing if a signature on this body matches four others
东海岸冲上岸的尸体吻合
that have washed up on beaches across the Eastern Seaboard.
- 什么特征？- 让我们查完再说
- What signature? - Let us check and we'll tell you.
看到了吗？
You see it?
对 看到了
Yeah, I see it.
是他干的
It's him.
等等 "他"是谁？
Wait, who's him?
未知嫌犯
The unknown subject, or unsub.
他在受害者肋骨上下穿刺孔洞
He punctures holes up and down his victims' rib cage.
为什么？
Why?
这关联死亡原因和方式
It speaks to cause and manner of death,
有助于建立犯罪特征
which helps establish a signature.
本案中是为了确保
In this case, to ensure
尸体灌满盐水下沉
the body fills with salt water and it sinks.
你觉得我这具尸体
And you think my dead guy
是你们连环案的一部分？
is part of your serial investigation?
现在确定是了
We do now.
能抓住他吗？
Can you stop him?
"水拥有完美记忆
"All water has a perfect memory
永远试图回归最初之地"
and is forever trying to get back to where it was."
托妮·莫里森
Toni Morrison.
好了 实习生
All right, trainee,
轮到你表现了
you're in the hot seat.
模拟演练 陈述案情
Practice round. Present the case.
目前五具尸体
Five bodies so far,
均因胸部刺伤相关联
connected via stab wounds to the chest.
所以刺击是他的性癖？
So stabbing is his paraphilia?
不 这是反侦查手段
No, it is a forensic countermeasure.
为何算反侦查？
Hmm. What makes it a countermeasure?
墨西哥湾流和海洋生物破坏
The Gulf Stream and marine life predation.
它们会毁掉受害者特征
They make victimology and trace evidence
和微量物证
almost impossible to discern.
还有两具尸体未确认身份
We haven't even identified two of the victims yet.
查清前别想理清时间线
Until we do, forget about an accurate timeline.
最后一个问题
All right. One last question.
你在逗我吗？
Are you kidding me with that?
哇 真可爱
Ooh. So cute.
他们还在让你带假枪？
They still make you carry a fake gun?
完成训练前都得这样
Just until I complete my training.
先适应配枪的重量
So I can get used to the weight of the service weapon on my hip.
暂时用这个凑合
Until then, I get by with this.
虽然不太一样
It's not quite the same thing, but
但有备无患总比
I'd rather have it and not need it than need it
- 临时抓瞎强 - 想法不错
- and not have it, you know? - That's nice.
外勤任务分配了吗？
You get your field office assignment yet?
这周出结果
It's happening this week.
有想去的吗？
Oh. Any requests?
首选华盛顿 离你们近
Number one is D.C. to be close to you guys, of course.
其次是
And, uh, number two
除了阿拉斯加安克雷奇都行
is anywhere but Anchorage, Alaska.
不喜欢雪？
Not a fan of the snow, huh?
受不了冬天每天
Not a fan of five and a half hours
五小时日照的日子
of sunlight during the winter.
又来？
Again?
半年第六次了
Sixth time in six months.
天 监察处还不罢休
Geez. OPR just won't give up.
第二轮模拟考 OPR全称是？
Yeah. Second practice round. What does OPR stand for?
职业责任办公室
Office of Professional Responsibility,
也就是FBI内务部
aka the FBI's Internal Affairs.
他们要审罗西多久？
How long are they gonna keep questioning Rossi?
直到得到想要的答案
Till they get the answers they want.
现在开始正式记录
All right. We're on the record.
探员贝阿特丽斯·卡尔
Agent Beatriz Carr
与高级监管探员大卫·罗西的谈话
with Supervisory Special Agent David Rossi.
今天状态如何 罗西探员？
How are you today, Agent Rossi?
好极了
Peachy.
我部门有些追加问题
My office has some additional questions
关于埃利亚斯·沃伊特在科利摩尔监狱
regarding the assault on Elias Voit
遇袭事件
at Collymore prison.
我的回答一如既往
My answer is as it has always been.
我不知情也未参与
I don't know how it happened.
我与此事毫无瓜葛
I played no role in it happening.
对
Yes.
你的说辞... 始终如一
You've been remarkably... consistent.
重申一遍 科利摩尔监狱是
Just to review, FCI Collymore is
联邦低设防监狱
a minimum security prison.
关押轻刑犯的地方
Filled with low-level offenders.
还有埃利亚斯·沃伊特
Oh, and Elias Voit.
对 外加沃伊特
Yes. And Elias Voit.
被两个跨州大麻贩子袭击
Who was attacked by two cannabis distributors
他们不该越界招惹
who made the mistake of crossing
- 州界线 - 所以你想问什么？
- state lines. - So, what's your question?
我刚收到
I just came into receipt
沃伊特转移前
of a conversation Mr. Voit had
的一段对话录音
before his transfer.
律师在场时
At the time, his lawyer was present,
监控是关闭的
so the cameras were off.
但FBI探员进入后
But once the FBI entered his cell,
保密协议失效
privilege no longer applied.
"FBI进入后"什么意思？
What do you mean, once the FBI entered?
正式声明 现在播放
For the record, I am now playing
罗西探员的2233号证据
exhibit 2233 for Agent Rossi.
警卫重启系统时
The guards were rebooting the system
你正好进入
when you entered.
麦克风比摄像头早启动
The microphones turned on before the cameras,
所以我们只有音频记录
so all we have is audio.
你以为能像胡迪尼越狱
I know you think you could Houdini out of Collymore,
但普通监区容不下连环杀手
but gen pop is no place for a serial killer.
达默 基比
Dahmer. Kibbe.
哈维
Harvey.
都死在狱友手里
All of them died at the hands of other prisoners.
因为用你的血
Because you build prison cred
能赚足牢里威望
by spilling blood like yours.
解释一下？
Can you explain this?
没必要
I don't need to.
你准确预言了他的遭遇
You told Voit exactly what would happen to him.
这不可疑吗？
That's not suspicious at all?
不 这是我的工作
No. It's my job.
预判反社会行为
To predict antisocial behavior.
是吗
Uh-huh.
能证明你与袭击无关吗？
And can you provide any evidence that you weren't responsible
- 沃伊特遇袭 - 无法证伪
- for the attack on Voit? - I can't prove a negative.
为你的职业生涯
For the sake of your career,
最好努力证明
I suggest you try.
如果我想埃利亚斯死
If I wanted Elias Voit dead,
他早就没命了
he would be dead.
但他还活着 不是吗？
Oh, and he's not dead, is he?
哦
Oh. -
你又来了？
You're here again?
对
Yeah.
忍不住
I can't help it.
很奇怪 他完全不像
It's so weird. He's so...
精神病患者
non-psychopathic.
有时会发出小狗般呜咽
You know, sometimes he makes little puppy noises.
就像... 这样
Like... Like that.
有进展吗？
Any update?
没 我是说...
No. I mean...
入院时就这样
This is what he was like when they brought him in.
可能明天醒 也可能永不
He could wake up tomorrow or never again.
最新核磁显示
His last MRI
前额叶和枕叶
indicated traumatic brain injury to his prefrontal
严重创伤
and occipital lobes.
- 奇怪的在后面 - 哦
- But that's not the weird part. - Oh.
他总不按常理出牌
It never is with him, is it?
脑部有复杂瘢痕
Voit has complex cerebral scarring,
部分损伤可追溯几十年
some of the damage goes back decades.
他的大脑像退役橄榄球员
His brain looks more like a retired linebacker
而非四十岁常人
than an average 40-year-old man.
当心
Oh, uh, be careful.
他只铐了一只手
Only one of his arms is cuffed.
没事
No, it's okay.
我亲自检查过 看着
I-I supervised this myself. Watch.
例行检查而已
Just a drill, thank you.
我知道为何而来
So... I know why I'm here.
- 你呢？ - 沃伊特的主治医生
- Why are you? - Voit's attending
拿到了监狱事件报告
got the final incident report from Collymore.
我要了复印件
I asked for a copy
帮罗西脱困
in the case it could get Rossi out of hot water.
昏迷了还操心
Man, you are in a coma,
罗西的事
and you're still all up in Rossi's business.
想不通
I can't figure out
他为何能活下来
how Voit is still alive.
洗衣房没监控
There were no cameras in the laundry room.
但报告显示
But according to the report,
他被刺三次后
he was stabbed three times,
反夺凶器
turned around, got the shank out
反杀两人后昏迷
of his attackers' hands, killed them and then collapsed.
激烈搏斗
That must have been one hell of a fight.
是啊
Yeah.
他怎么做到的？
So, how did he do it?
老天...
Mother...
- 怎么 - 这语气我熟
- What... - Ooh. I recognize that tone.
不是老公就是孩子
Either your husband or your kids did something
惹你生气
to get under your skin.
差不多
In the ballpark.
威尔他妈要来庆生
Will's mom is flying in for Michael's birthday.
上次她来
Last time she did that,
给迈克买了仓鼠
she decided to surprise all of us
"惊喜"
when she got Michael a hamster.
我宁愿跟你换
Honestly, I would trade with you.
- 怎么啦？- 我爸非要
- Why? What's up? - My dad wants
见见丽贝卡 好让他...
to meet Rebecca so he can--
原话是...
and this is a direct quote--
"掂量下她斤两"
"size her up."
嗯 行吧
Mm. Okay.
代沟吧 估计不认可
Different generation. Probably doesn't approve.
但不是你想的那种不认可
Yeah, but not in the way that you think.
我之前嫁了个白人 他本来就不爽
I mean, I was married to a white guy before,
现在我和女人认真交往
which he wasn't crazy about,
他更接受不了
and now I'm getting serious with a woman.
他觉得是我的择偶观
And he's convinced that it's his parenting
反映了他教育失败
that's resulted in my choice of partners.
但你知道这不是事实
Yeah, well, we know that's not true.
呃...
Eh...
溺亡案有新进展
Good news on our ocean drownings.
当地确认了最新死者身份
Locals just made a positive ID
大卫·哈特尔
on the most recent victim. Guy's name is David Hartle.
海滨城怎么这么快确认的？
How'd Ocean City ping him so fast?
纯属运气
Sheer luck.
寒流改变了凶手抛尸的海流
Cold front changed the currents on the unsub.
哈特尔比其他尸体更快冲上岸
So Hartle washed up quicker than the others.
但愿他身上还有
Fingers crossed, there's a clue on him
没被海水冲掉
that wasn't washed away
或鱼啃食的线索
or eaten by fish.
验尸报告到了吗？
Do we have the ME report here?
- 刚到 - 太好了
- Yeah, just came in. - Oh, great.
肺里有雾化芬太尼
Guy had aerosolized fentanyl in his lungs.
剂量不足以致死
Not enough for an overdose.
但足以短暂昏迷
But enough to knock him out temporarily.
看这个
And check this out.
牙齿上有褐色残留物
There was brown residue found on his teeth.
法医鉴定是泳池牙石
The ME identified it as swimmer's calculus.
和水质酸碱度有关对吧？
Okay, this has to do with the pH of the water, right?
对
Yeah.
海水pH值8.1左右
Ocean water pH is about 8.1.
水质碱性越强 pH值越高
The more alkaline the water, the higher the pH,
牙齿染色越严重
the more it stains the teeth.
这种牙石通常由...
The most common cause of this kind of swimmer's calculus is...
- 氯元素 - 答对了
- Chlorine. - Bingo.
等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
你是说哈特尔
You're telling us that David Hartle
是在泳池溺亡而非海里？
drowned in a pool and not the ocean?
根据牙科记录 是的
According to those dental records, yeah.
法医也不敢相信
The ME couldn't believe it either.
所以他在死者胸口钻孔
Okay, so he's not stabbing his victims in the chest
不是反侦查手段？- 确定？
- as a countermeasure. - Are you sure?
他是为确保尸体下沉
He needs to make sure the bodies sink.
这不算反侦查吗？- 算
Isn't that still a countermeasure? - ALVEZ: Yeah.
但这是误导方向
But it's a misdirect.
他想让我们盯着海洋
He wants us to look in the ocean
不 当然不是
No, of course not.
而且海洋环境太不可控
Plus the ocean's... it's too chaotic.
凶手需要的是
I mean, it would have to be
完全掌控的场所
an environment that he had complete control.
能无限延长虐待时间的地方
One where he could extend the torture for as long as he wants.
他在自家后院
He's drowning them
淹死受害者
in his own backyard.
我不行了...
I can't...
求求你...
Please...
求你了...
我好累
I'm so tired.
撑不住了...
I can't...
不行了...
不 我绝不妥协
No. I'm not doing that.
戴夫 别这样
Ugh, Dave, come on.
艾米丽 不行
Emily, no. -
为什么？
Why not?
有什么用？
What good will it do?
这是科利摩尔监狱
This is the incident report
洗衣房事件报告
from the laundry room at Collymore.
不该一起看看吗？
Don't you think we should review it?
我看过 你也看过
I did. I read it. You read it.
里面没有证据能证明
There's nothing in there that proves
我没指使人捅沃伊特
that I didn't have Voit shanked.
但监狱调查组不是我们
But the Bureau of Prisons investigative unit isn't us.
也许我们能发现
Maybe if we put our heads together
他们忽略的细节
we can see something they missed.
不...
Uh... no.
为什么？
Why not?
听着
Listen.
自从沃伊特昏迷后
Ever since Voit's been in a coma,
我不再探视和交谈
I stopped seeing him, I stopped talking to him.
我不想做任何
I don't want to do anything
可能唤醒他的事
that might make that happen.
再次
Again.
好 那别跟他说话
Okay. Then don't talk to him.
跟我说
Talk to me.
我们付出太多
We have worked too hard
不能让沃伊特毁你事业
to let Voit take your job away now.
你最初看报告时...
When you first looked at the report...
...注意到什么？
...what did you notice?
漂白剂
Bleach.
我也注意到 凶手身上有
Me too. It was found on one of the attackers.
沃伊特反击时泼的
So Voit got a shot in.
但没起什么作用
Yeah, but it didn't help.
凶手还是压制了他
They still overpowered him.
第二处疑点呢？
What was the second thing?
清洁用品
Cleaning supplies.
从柜子摔落散了一地
They fell off the closet onto the floor.
但部分物品散落距离
But some of the contents fell as far
足有五英尺 这不可能
as five feet away. Now that wouldn't
仅是撞到柜子造成的
happen from a simple collision with the closet.
冲击力明显过大
There too much velocity involved.
这说明当时...
Yeah, that happened because...
沃伊特在柜子里
He was r-reaching
找藏匿的东西...
for something in there...
私藏的武器
...that he'd hidden.
联邦监狱局没发现
FBOP didn't find anything.
有意思
Huh.
沃伊特被刺伤口多深？
How deep were the shank wounds on Voit?
约一英寸
About one inch.
凶手身上的呢？
And how about his attackers?
六英寸
Six inches.
这很不寻常 对吧？
That seems a little strange, doesn't it?
调查组认为沃伊特是自卫
The investigators theorized that Voit was fighting for his life.
所以他不只是刺伤对方
So he didn't just stab them, he
而是全力捅入要害
drove the shank in as deep as he could.
你信这套说辞吗？
And are you buying what they're selling you?
他们别无其他推论
They had no other conclusions to draw.
没有证据 无法证实
No evidence, no proof.
但我们都了解沃伊特
Yeah, but we both know Voit.
你相信吗？
Are you buying it?
唯一合理的解释是
It would only make sense
沃伊特藏了其他武器
if Voit had another weapon.
啊
Ah.
- 嗯 - 怎么？
- Hmm. - What?
我要进洗衣房查看
I need to get into that laundry room.
能安排吗？
Can you make that happen?
应该可以 为什么？
I guess. Why?
先安排再说
You just make it happen.
关键点在于
Here's the thing.
如果受害者溺亡在泳池
If these victims are drowning in a pool--
牙齿被氯水染色这么久
I mean, long enough for their teeth to stain brown--
说明他们挣扎数小时
it means they're treading for hours.
泳池必须深到踩不到底
Yeah, so the pool has to be deep enough that they can't touch.
很可能是定制泳池
That means it's probably custom-built.
七英尺均深
Seven feet all around.
他享受看猎物精疲力尽
He gets off on watching them get tired.
逐渐放弃挣扎 然后...
Slowly succumb, and then...
通过不施救获得掌控感
he feels this power in choosing not to save them.
类似窒息癖好
Like a submersion or asphyxiation fetish.
但受害者特征不一致
Yeah, but with no consistent victimology.
可能不是性冲动犯罪
You know, I might be wrong, but this doesn't read as sexual.
更像是通过受害者
It's more like he's trying to work
宣泄某种心结
something out through his victims.
恐水症很常见
Well, aquaphobia is incredibly common.
46%美国人害怕深水区
Something like 46% of Americans fear deep water
64%害怕开放水域...
in pools, and 64% of them fear open water, so...
你推测凶手曾经历溺水
So what you're saying is something drowning-related
现在通过绑架重现
happened to this guy and now he's revisiting it
类似场景？
on everyone he kidnaps?
很有可能
Yeah, possibly.
更怪的案子都有
I mean, we've... we've seen weirder.
各位！有新发现！
Yo! Yo, yo, yo!
看这里！
Over here!
来得正好！
Ah, right on cue. - GARCIA: Yo!
快来看！
Come! Friendships come!
虽然不优雅也不含蓄
Okay, it's not demure or mindful,
但这太疯狂了
but, yo, this is nuts.
就像那种长牙哺乳动物...
This is like, uh, the mammals with the teeth...
像花栗鼠囤坚果似的
Like Chip and Dale nuts, like,
"需要多少水才能...
"how much water does it take
佩内洛普
Penelope.
- 发现了什么？- 首先
- What did you find? - Firstly,
疑似受害者切特·威廉姆斯失踪
possible victim Chet Williams has been reported missing.
常去特拉华冲浪 最后出现地
Fan of the Delaware surf. That's where he was last seen.
已确认受害者和切特
The identified victims and Chet
搜索记录显示都访问过
all recently visited, according to their search history,
AirBeachAndBed网站
AirBeachAndBed.com.
全部都是 看出关联了吗？
All of them. What do you make of it, huh?
不明白 受害者们
I don't get it. The victims
都在找度假屋？
were all looking for vacation rentals?
海滨度假屋
Beach rentals, specifically.
凶手如何获取这些信息？
But how would he get ahold of that information?
他在网站工作？
Does he work there?
不一定
Well, he wouldn't have to.
用户数据常被卖给
I mean, user information gets sold all the time
数据经纪人  信用卡公司
to data brokers, credit card companies, marketers.
凶手可能潜伏其中
So, one of these companies could be hiding our unsub.
不能把侧写交给警方
Then we shouldn't deliver this profile to the police.
直接联系网站运营方
We need to talk to whoever runs this website.
告诉他们用户正被
And tell them their users
连环杀手盯上？
are targets of a serial killer?
他们不会承认的
They won't admit to anything.
否则要担法律责任
They can't without risking liability.
不需要他们承认
They don't have to.
提供侧写就能施压
Maybe delivering the profile could be enough.
嗯
Uh-huh.
是我
Hey, it's me.
需要你帮忙
I need your help with something.
感谢到场
Thank you for coming.
我代表司法部
On behalf of the Department of Justice,
感谢贵司配合调查
we appreciate you agreeing to assist us in this matter.
理解各位作为说客
We also appreciate that, as lobbyists
需遵守保密协议
for a rental property website,
- 签署过保密协议 - 所以你们清楚
- you have all signed NDAs. - Then you know
我们无法充分配合
that's gonna limit how much we can cooperate.
我们理解
We do.
希望贵司利用影响力
We are just hoping that you will use the sway
协助调查
you have with your website to help us in our investigation.
你怎么确定有连环杀手？
How do you know there is a killer?
新闻里完全没报道
I haven't seen anything about it in the papers.
当然不会 我们通常不会向公众
Well, you wouldn't. We don't normally share
透露正在调查的案件细节
the details of an ongoing investigation
除非这对调查有帮助
with general public unless, of course,
比如现在的情况
it can help with our investigation.
我们并非指控任何人
We are not accusing anyone of any wrongdoing.
只是请求协助
We are just asking for your assistance.
凶手作案手法缜密
This unknown subject is methodical,
好吧
Okay.
开始了
Here we go.
现在观察他们的微表情
Now we look for their micro-expressions.
看看这些人会无意中
See what these guys give away
泄露什么信息
without realizing they're giving it away.
这群人难道不会更擅长伪装？
Won't this crowd have a better poker face than that?
没人能控制杏仁核的应激反应
You can't control an involuntary response from the amygdala.
再厉害的扑克脸也没用
No matter how good you think you are at bluffing.
别问
Don't ask.
- 我偏要问 - 说了别问
- Now I have to. - I just said don't ask.
按惯例他们会先大声否认
Okay. If they stick to form,
比如前排那个穿西装的白人
they'll start with a loud denial.
他们事先指定的发言人
Most likely from
就是他
a previously agreed-upon spokesperson. Him.
- 前排那个衣冠楚楚的白人？- 对
- Dapper white dude, front row? - Yep.
我锁定他了！
Ooh, I got him!
受害者
...victims.
我们是谷歌之外
Well, we are one of the most
最受欢迎的度假搜索平台
popular vacation search sites after Google.
我们无法控制用户行为
We can't control that.
希望贵司提供员工名单
Well, we're hoping you'll give us a list
及第三方数据经纪人信息
of your employees and third party brokers
- 绝对不行
who access your data. - Absolutely not.
我们不出售用户数据
We don't sell our data.
这在服务条款里
The company's very clear about that
写得很清楚
in its terms of service.
可能是数据泄露
Could be a breach.
不存在泄露
There are no breaches.
至少不会公开承认
That you can admit to publicly.
但我们保证
But we assure you
所有协助
that any help you can give us will stay
都将保密
confidential.
我们不会继续配合
We're not cooperating any further.
好了 塔拉
All right, Tara.
白脸唱够了
That's enough good cop.
直说吧
Let's cut to the chase.
你们网站盈利模式不是租房
Your website's business model isn't based
而是贩卖用户数据
on getting people into rentals.
每个点击"接受Cookie"的人
It's based on selling out anyone
都会被出卖
who taps that "accept cookies" button.
有人利用这点
Someone is exploiting that
谋杀无辜
to kill innocent men and women.
前排右侧
Front row, right side.
那是谁？
Who's that?
理查德·唐尼
Richard Downey.
怎么了？
Why?
听到"谋杀"时他低头了
He looked down when she said "kill."
公司高价购买用户数据
Companies pay big money for your users.
这是数字经济的一部分
We have accepted that as a part of the digital economy.
但我们不接受
But what we don't accept
你们把五条人命当作盈利代价
is you treating five victims as acceptable losses
只为完成季度财报
so you could make your quarterly earnings.
我们认为这些谋杀案
And we think that their murders
恕我直言
With all due respect,
比你们的退休金计划重要得多
their murders are more important than your 401K.
这是本能反应
That looks involuntary to me.
- 他隐瞒什么？- 不清楚
- What's he hiding? - I don't know.
唐尼在斯坦福读完MBA
What I can tell you is that Downey got his MBA
曾在伊拉克
at Stanford after serving
服役三次
three tours of duty in Iraq.
- 连续服役？- 没错
- Back to back? - Yes indeedy.
我还留着军籍牌
I still got my dog tags.
你呢？
You got yours?
当然
Yes indeedy.
嘿
Hey.
这个整岁生日惊喜如何？
So, how is this for a birthday that ends in zero?
简直... 说不出话
I mean, this is... speechless.
美到窒息那种
Like, "take my breath away" speechless.
怎么找到这里的？
How did you even find this place?
搜"完美日落度假地"
I looked up "perfect sunset getaways,"
- 就跳出来了 - 确实完美
- and this came up. - Well, it is perfect.
不
No.
- 现在才完美 - 别
- This is perfect. - Oh, no, no.
- 还没到送礼环节 - 没事
- It's not time for gifts yet. - No, it's okay.
打开吧
Just open it.
啊
Ah.
谢谢？
Thanks?
翻过来看
Turn it over.
哒哒！
Ta-da! -
"敬你的肝"？过分了
"Here's to your liver"? Come on,
我没那么酗酒吧？
I'm not that much of a lush, am I?
- 当然没有 - 除了生日那天
- No... - Well, only on your birthday,
谁知道呢
I don't know.
等等！要自拍吗？
Oh, wait! Selfie time?
- 要！- 别 我状态好差
- Yeah, yeah, yeah! - Honey, no, no, no, I look terrible.
超美的 我想留个纪念
No, no, no, you look great, plus I want to remember this.
- 好吧 - 来
- Okay. - Come on.
爸 靠近点
Oh, wait, Dad, tuck in, get closer.
好 我该看哪里？
Okay, all right, where am I looking?
看右边的小孔
You're looking at the pinhole on the right.
明白
All right.
- 好 笑一个 - 好
- Okay, smile. - Okay.
笑
And smile.
- 多拍几张 - 在拍了
- Take lots, take a bunch. - I am, I am.
好了 然后...
Okay, and...
给我看看
All right, let me see.
我有否决权
I get veto power.
妈 你超美的
Okay, Mom, you look great.
好吧
Okay.
哇 拍得真好
Oh, these are awesome.
这几张挺可爱的
These are kind of cute.
这他妈怎么回事？
What the hell is this?
唐尼先生 我是FBI探员阿尔维斯
Mr. Downey, I'm SSA Alvez with the FBI.
这位是格林探员
This is Agent Green.
我们有几个后续问题
We just have a few follow-up
关于溺亡案想请教
questions we wanted to ask you about the drowning case.
我被捕了吗？
Am I under arrest?
- 没有 - 那为什么带我来？
- No. - Then why am I here?
因为你们拒绝配合
'Cause we already told you no.
你们服过役又怎样？
So you guys served, so what?
我们知道你现在进退两难
We know that you're being pulled in two different
左右为难
directions right now.
作为员工要守规矩
Look, on one hand, you're an employee.
但你也曾宣誓
On the other, you swore an oath
保卫宪法抵御外敌
to protect the Constitution against all enemies
包括国内威胁
foreign and domestic.
我们只想阻止
All we're trying to do is stop
其中一名敌人
one of those enemies.
利用你们网站作恶的人
Okay? Someone who is using your website against you.
就算我想帮 也做不到
Even if I wanted to, I couldn't.
你可以
Yes, you can.
我们会教你开个后门
We'll tell you how to open up
剩下的交给我们
a back door to the site. We can do the rest.
行不通
That won't work.
技术部门会发现是我
IT will flag it, they'll know it's me.
提前剧透
And spoiler alert,
公司最恨告密者
my company is not a big fan of whistleblowers.
那么...
Well...
该我出场了
that's where I come in.
爸 我们还有选择吗？
Dad, what choice do we have?
嘿 冷静
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
嘘...
Shh, shh, shh.
不行 这事没得商量
No, okay? This is not happening.
明白吗？绝对不行
Do you understand? It's not.
- 爸 他... - 不行！
- Dad, he-he... - It's not!
这么做我们就完了
If we do this, we're dead.
快上车
I said get in.
我相信你
I trust you.
不
No.
我不会让你...
No, I'm not gonna let you do this...
好了 上车
Okay. Get in.
好
Okay.
等等 那爸怎么办？
Okay. Wait. W-Wait. What about Dad?
不会有事的 快走
It's gonna be okay. Just do it.
好吧 好吧
Uh, okay. Okay.
会没事的
WOMAN It's gonna be okay.
可爸还在那边
But Dad. But Dad's right there.
好了
All right.
我踩不到底...
Oh, I can't... I can't touch the bottom.
我也踩不到
Neither can I.
哪里都够不着
I can't touch it anywhere.
让开
Move.
薇薇安 脱掉衣服
Vivian, take off your clothes,
减轻负重
anything that's gonna weigh you down.
没事的
It's okay.
会好的
Gonna be okay.
- 相信我 - 好
- Just trust me. - Okay.
满意了吗？变态！
Oh, is this what you want? You creep!
闭嘴 别说话
Stop. Stop talking.
为什么？
Why?
要保存体力
'Cause we're gonna need our energy. Don't steal
全部体力
All of it.
伊万探员还没回复...
Agent Ivan needs to get back to us, and...
等一下
Give me a minute.
想玩真人版《妙探寻凶》吗？
You want to play a real-life game of Clue with me?
怎么感觉你已经赢了
Why do I feel like you've already won?
- 或许 - 我先来
- Maybe. - I'll start.
沃伊特教授在洗衣房用...
Professor Voit in the laundry room with a...
电扇罩做的凶器
Shank made from the wired cover of a fan.
- 什么鬼？ - 沃伊特自制的
- What in the world? - A weapon
防身武器
that Voit made to fight off his attackers.
- 你怎么知道？- 他说的
- How'd you know? - He told me.
我有滤水器
I got stuff, I got filtered water,
有电扇
got a fan.
怎么找到的？
But how did you find it?
每台洗衣机下都有排水盘
Every washing machine has a drain pan underneath it.
根据警卫发现他的位置
Based on where the guards found Voit's body,
只有那里能藏武器
there was only one place he could have hidden it.
现在知道他怎么反杀了
So now we know how he fought them off.
但他怎么知道会遇袭？
But how did he know they were coming?
他在低安保监狱
He was in a minimum-security prison.
那两人不是杀手
Those two weren't killers.
查过案底
I checked their records.
刑期都很长
They were gonna be in there for a while.
- 被收买了？- 对
- So they were enticed? - Yeah.
但沃伊特用化名入狱
Okay, but Voit wasn't in there as Voit.
登记的是本名李·杜瓦尔
He was registered under his birth name, Lee Duval.
有人泄露了秘密
Well, someone let the cat out of the bag.
除了我们
So, besides us,
还有谁知道他身份？
who knew Voit was Voit?
- 你 别动 - 我？
- You. Freeze. - Moi?
听说你最近总去陪护沃伊特？
What is this that I hear about you
守在他床边？
sitting bedside with Voit?
- 没什么 - 肯定有事
- It's nothing. - It's something.
难道在给他读睡前故事？
I mean, what, are you reading him a bedtime story?
没 你过来看
No. Come here.
好
Okay.
是这样的
So,
记得上次和沃伊特出外勤时
do you remember the last time we were in the field with Voit,
我不得不阻止他和泰勒互相残杀吗？
and I had to stop him and Tyler from killing each other?
记得你摘了眼镜
I remember you taking off your glasses.
- 那是你认真的标志 - 没错
- How I knew you were serious. - Right.
当时我直视他的眼睛
So I looked in his eyes.
深入他的内心 看到了...
And I mean, I went deep in there, and I saw...
某些东西
...stuff.
什么？
What?
灵魂的痕迹
A soul.
少来了 - 不...
Oh, all right, come on. - No, I...
我知道他是反社会人格
I know. I know. He-He's a psychopath.
但我必须告诉你我的观察
All I can do is tell you what I saw,
那里有尚未熄灭的火星
and I saw an ember of something.
好吧
Okay.
反正我什么都没看出来
Yeah, I don't see anything, all right?
但我相信你的判断
But I believe that you believe it.
谢谢
Thank you.
我想知道的是
Here's what I want to know.
你守在他床边能得到什么？
What do you get from sitting next to him now?
我希望...
I'm hoping...
能找到他残存的人性
I can see something salvageable in him.
遇到你之前我从不胃痛
You know, I never got heartburn before I met you. Never.
是我过度的同理心作祟
It's my freakish empathy.
让你起鸡皮疙瘩了？
It's giving you the heebies.
但我的科学理性
But I can stave off the jeebies
能让我保持专业
because I have done some good work on this case.
- 能看看吗？- 请便
- May I? - Ah.
那个网站的内鬼提供的
So, that mole we got from the website?
受害者用户数据
I got the user data of our victims.
全在这里
All of them.
包括那两个未确认的？
Including the two that we couldn't ID?
对 米拉·史蒂文斯和乔尔·坦纳
Yeah, including them. This is Mila Stevens and Joel Tanner.
他们符合当地警方
They were the missing people
提供的
that most closely match
失踪者特征
what little the local police could give us.
在时间线上处于什么位置？
All right. Where are they on the timeline with the other victims?
第一和第二位受害者
Numbers one and two.
原籍哪里？
Okay. Where are they originally from?
弗吉尼亚州切萨皮克
Chesapeake, Virginia, both of them.
首案往往包含最多线索
All right, first victims always tell us the most
凶手当时还在摸索模式
because the unsub is still learning, so what did he learn?
根据这张地图显示
Based on this map?
他学会了要跨区域作案
That he should go 100 miles in a different direction
- 避免在本地狩猎 - 明白了
- to find his next victim. - All right,
所以杀害米拉和乔尔后
so maybe after Mila and Joel,
他不再犯新手错误
he stopped making the rookie mistake
不再在自家后院作案
of hunting in his own backyard.
如果他住在切萨皮克附近
If he lives in or around Chesapeake,
泳池可能就在那里
that could be where his pool is.
切萨皮克 定制七英尺泳池 马上查
Chesapeake, custom pools, seven feet. On it.
你能同时处理多个搜索吗？
All right, now can you do more than one search at a time?
科学研究表明
Ooh, science says
问蠢问题会降低魅力值
asking a dumb question makes you less cute.
当然可以
Uh, yes, I can.
听着
All right, um, look,
促使他开始杀人的原因
whatever made this guy start killing
可能也发生在切萨皮克
in this way might have happened in Chesapeake, too.
查查当地溺水相关创伤事件
So, let's-let's look at, um, some water-based trauma.
溺水 踩水挣扎
Drowning, treading water.
调取救生员事故报告
Check lifeguard incident reports in the area.
双线搜索 开始
Double quest. Here we go.
哦
Oh.
我的胃痛突然神奇消失了
It's like my heartburn has just magically gone away.
因为我是治愈系天才
Yeah, I'm a healer, that's why.
确实如此
You are. You are. -
我们怎么办？
Oh. What do we do?
怎么办啊？
What do we do? What do we do?
试着...
Just, um, try...
漂浮起来
Just, um... just float.
- 什么？- 像这样
- What? - Okay? Like this. Just...
保持漂浮
Just float. Just float.
放松身体
Just float.
什么声音？
What?
天啊 不...
Oh, my God. Oh.
- 求你别这样 - 不！
- Please. No, please, please don't do this. - No.
等等...
Pl... Hey.
不 不要！
What... No, no, no, no.
- 没必要这样做 - 求你了
- You don't have to do this. Please. - No, please. Please. Oh.
不！
No.
- 妈 怎么办？- 我...
- Mom, what do we do? - Um... um...
- 怎么办？- 试着...
- What do we do? - Just, uh...
潜下去
Get under it.
- 快潜下去 - 好
- Come on, just get under it. - Okay.
- 准备好了？- 嗯
- Okay? - Okay.
现在怎么办？
What do we do?
你没必要这样做！
You don't have to do this!
能抓住什么吗？
Is there anything you can grab?
没有...
Oh. Uh...
什么都没有
No. No.
- 池壁呢？- 试过了 太滑
- The walls? - No, I tried.
没有可抓的地方
There's nothing to hold on to.
我不想死
I don't want to die.
看着我
Hey, look at me.
- 嘿 - 不 我不想...
- Hey. - No, I don't... I don't want...
你不会死的
You're not gonna die.
绝对不会
You're not.
好了
All right.
明白吗？
Okay?
放慢呼吸
Slow it down.
对 就这样
Good. That's it.
柯蒂斯  克丽丝蒂和薇薇安·埃斯特斯
Curtis, Kristi and Vivian Estes.
柯蒂斯的母亲报案称他们
Reported missing by Curtis' mom
参加生日派对后失踪
when they didn't return home from a birthday party.
能确定是
And we're sure
我们凶手所为？- 地理范围吻合
this is our unsub? - GREEN: Well, geographically, it fits.
在切萨皮克海滩被绑
They were taken from a beach off Chesapeake.
这是重大升级
That's a huge escalation.
为什么绑架整个家庭？
Why would he take a whole family?
或许有答案了
We might have an answer to that.
这是福勒一家
Meet the Fowler family.
十五年前 母亲  父亲和女儿
Fifteen years ago, mother, father and daughter
被发现溺亡在泳池盖布下
were found drowned under their pool tarp.
唯一嫌疑人是儿子富兰克林
The only suspect was their son Franklin.
当时仅十岁
He was ten at the time.
等等 你是说
Wait, so you're saying
- 他杀了全家？- 警方当年
- he killed his own family? - Well, the cops
无法证实 但父亲是救生员
couldn't prove it at the time, but Dad was a lifeguard
富兰克林没通过游泳考试
and Franklin couldn't pass his swimming test.
没人会因游泳考试杀全家
You don't kill your whole family over a swimming test.
但如果你有哮喘
You do if you suffer from asthma
父亲酗酒并强迫你练习
and your dad's a drunk that makes you take it
所以
Okay, so,
凶手此前行事克制
up till now, the unsub was disciplined.
- 选择不同受害者 - 直到看见埃斯特斯家
- He varied his victimology. - Till he saw the Estes.
让他想起自己的家庭
They reminded him of his own family.
有地址吗？
We have an address?
县界附近的独立房产
It's an isolated property close to the county line,
明白
All right.
准备行动
Let's get ready to roll.
你也来 快
You too. Come on.
妈 我... 没力气了
Mom, I'm... I'm getting tired.
不知道还能撑多久...
I don't know how much longer I can...
我知道 我知道
I know. I know.
好了
Okay.
我们...
Let's, uh...
我试着...
I'm gonna try to...
妈... 你撑不住的
Mom... You can't do that forever.
- 怎么了？- 没事
- What is it? - It's nothing.
- 真的没事 - 看着我
- Nothing. I'm okay. - Hey, just look at me.
抓紧我
Hang onto me. -
抓紧了 我在
I got you. I got you.
找到富兰克林·福勒的房产许可
Hey, hey, I found zoning permits on Franklin Fowler's property.
去年安装了七英尺泳池
Last year he installed a seven-foot pool.
确认凶手 出发
That's definitely our unsub. Let's go.
能换真枪吗？
Any way I could trade up to a real gun?
不行
No.
不行了 撑不住了
I can't. I can't do it anymore.
没事的 休息下...
That's okay. Just take a break.
要我来...
Do you want me to...
- 我可以下去 换我撑 - 不行
- I can go down. I can take a turn. - No. No.
只会消耗更快
It'll just tire us out faster.
我快够到...
I can almost...
要是能抓住什么...
If I could just hold... hold on to something.
坚持住 再撑一下
Hang on. Hang on a second.
试试这个
Here, try this.
快 用力
Come on. Come on.
有效了 抓紧我
Oh, it's working. All right, just hang on to me.
你们从正门进 我们绕后
You guys take the house. We'll go in the back.
下潜！
Dive!
有枪击！
Shots fired!
富兰克林·福勒
Franklin Fowler,
放下武器！
drop the weapon!
别犯傻
Don't do it.
打死我 谁救他们？
Shoot me, how you gonna save them?
没这玩意儿可不行
Without this.
或许...
Or maybe...
这正是他的计划
that was the plan all along.
自求多福
Good luck.
救命！- 坚持住！
Help! - Just hang on!
我妈中枪了
My mom's been shot.
- 在努力！- 就在那里
- We're trying! - Right there.
救命！- 割断它！
Help! - Cut it!
快割！- 救命！
Just cut it! - VIVIAN: Help!
撑住
Hang on.
我们来了
We're coming.
坚持住！
Hang on!
让开！
Move!
快走！
Go!
抓住她了
I got her.
抓住了？- 抓住了
You got her? - GREEN: I got her.
我妈...
My mom...
抓住你了
I got you.
没事了
You're okay.
我不行了
I can't.
安全
Clear.
妈妈
Mommy.
我们救回她了
We got her back.
她会没事的
She's gonna be okay.
让让 急救人员通过
All right. Coming through, please.
干得漂亮
All right. Hey, nice work.
谢了 你也是
Thanks, man. You too.
哦
Oh.
这谁的？
Who-Whose is that?
- 不是我的 - 是我的
- Not me. - Uh, it's mine.
哇
Oh, wow.
- 怎么了？- 我的外勤分配下来了 - 快看
- What is it? - I got my field assignment. - Hey.
阿拉斯加？
Anchorage?
不 阿拉巴马州莫比尔
No. Mobile, Alabama.
不错嘛
All right. - Huh. That's not bad.
是不错 但...
It's not. I just, uh...
舍不得离开BAU
I guess I don't want to leave the BAU.
理解你...
Aw. Well...
- 又不是永远 - 对
It's not forever. - No.
五年而已对吧？
It's just five years, right?
嗯...
Mm... Mm.
对吧？
Right?
五年后升职
It's five years until you make the jump
当上特别主管探员
to supervisory special agent.
再熬十年才能进BAU
And then ten years until you can join the BAU.
十年？
Ten?
对 整整十年
Yeah. It's, uh, it's ten.
节哀吧菜鸟
Sorry, champ.
后会无期
Good knowing you, rookie.
也就十年嘛
Only a decade.
十年啊
Ten.
进
Come in. -
所以...
So...
查不到谁泄露沃伊特在低安监狱
...no luck on who knew Voit was in minimum security.
不过找到他的武器
Let me tell you this, finding his weapon
让OPR对我态度缓和不少
earned me some good will with OPR.
不代表你没指使袭击
That doesn't mean you didn't do it.
审我那探员
You know, that agent who's been on my ass
也这么说 - 没错
has made that same point. - Yes,
典型的内务部策略
it sounds like classic internal affairs strategy.
给你足够绳子自缢
Give you just enough rope to hang yourself.
但我明天还能上班
Yeah, well, I get to show up for work tomorrow, but I'm
- 知足了 - 很好
- good with that. - Good.
我们需要你
Because we need you.
有新麻烦了
We have a new problem.
又怎么了？
Now what?
溺亡案凶手自杀前说
Our drowning unsub said something weird
奇怪的话
before he killed himself.
说这"全是计划的一部分"
That this was "part of the plan" all along.
泰勒报告里提到过
Yeah, I read that in Tyler's report.
技术组扫完他手机
Well, when the techs finished the sweep of his phone,
发现他录了
they found that he took video
所有受害者溺亡过程
of all of the victims he drowned.
如果走运的话
Now, maybe, if we're lucky,
这就是他的"计划"
that's what he meant by "plan."
但我觉得没这么简单
So why do I feel we're not that lucky?
视频上传到私人VPN云盘
He uploaded the videos to a private VPN cloud.
用的加密技术
And he used some of the same technology that Voit used
和沃伊特建网络时一样
to build his network.
- 果然有关联 - 等等
- All right, here we go. - Okay, hang on.
别又和空气对话
Don't start talking to people who aren't there.
目前都是间接证据
What we have so far is circumstantial.
但他用的编解码器...
It's just that the encrypted codec he used...
- 编解码器是啥？- 呃...
- What the hell is codec? - Uh...
是压缩
it's the software
和解压
for compressing and decompressing
数据的软件
large amounts of data.
恐怖分子和维基解密都用过
Terrorists use it. Uh, WikiLeaks, they use it.
其实很常见
It's-it's widely available.
你信这套说辞？
You buy that?
我是说
All I'm saying is there are
其他可能性太多
a lot of other explanations
得先排除
and we need to rule them out
才能确定沃伊特是否参与
before we can assume that Voit's a part of this somehow.
但我们都了解沃伊特
Yeah, but we both know Voit.
你信自己说的话吗？
So, do you buy what you're selling?
不信
No.
借过借过
Oops, oops, excuse me.
- 帮忙开个门？- 好
- Do you mind getting that door? - No.
- 谢啦 - 客气
- Thank you. - Not at all.
翻译合成：Deepseek / zpwz